Guide to the Kate Bornstein papers 1910-2018
Brown University Library
- Electronic records on removable carriers
  - 16mm Kodachrome film (small box): "Sightseeing tour, Boston - Nov. '58, AHB and Sam Vandam, football game?", 1958 (Box 19)
  - 16mm Kodachrome film (small box): "Skowhegan, Maine, July '66", 1966 (Box 19)
  - 16mm Kodachrome film (small box): "Wagon wheel, Paul, Virginia, 9/55", 1955 (Box 19)
  - audio cassette: "Fresh Air with Terry Gross;" contains interview with Kate Bornstein, 1997 (Box 19)
  - audio cassette: "Kate on Fog City Radio", n.d. (Box 19)
  - audio cassette: "Overture opening monnologue theme", n.d. (Box 19)
  - audio cassette: "Tosha Silver astrologer/psycic, Kate", 2000 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "20/20 Barbara Walters re: trans kids", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Alternatives 1-35, 51 pages, 2 copies on good paper, 1 copy on regular", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Alternatives 36-74, Sept. 30, 05", 2005 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Alternatives, 65 pages, 3 copies, as of 1 Sept 05", 2005 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "[Alternatives] 76-101, Sept 05", 2005 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Amsterdam 07 photos by BC plus movie of Kate's Passion Fruit award", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Archived files mid Jan 06", 2006 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Australia [?] slideshow ?", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Barbara's Costa Rica pix", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "BBC Interview with Laura Knight Jadczyk", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Blonde in a Bottle" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Blondes abroad slides" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Blonde's out of Africa: All Kate's photos, raw and edited; Barbara's for website" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Blonde's out of Africa: All pix raw and edited, backup copy" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Costa Rica dig pix", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Cruel Desire, 2 copies, [?], 24 pgs each", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Cruel quickstart, 24 pgs, 3 copies pls.", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Deep intro 2007 master" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Derek and Romaine Show, Sirius Out Q, queer favs 06, winner Kate Bornstein", 2006 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Diana Cage Show, Sirius Out Q, 16 Nov 2007, Barbara and Kate" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Driving Miss Crazy", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Dying to be Thin", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Eye of (a) Starbuck", 2009 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Even Outlaws Get the Blues, final master", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "FFE [?] censorship PJT [?], nursing baby images, lo-res", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Galleries thru Oct, 2001" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Hello Cruel book, 7 August 2005" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Hello Cruel draft, 2 Aug 2005" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Hello Cruel illustrations, Oct 13, 05", 2005 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Hello Cruel World, Sept 30, 2005" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Hello Cruel World, Dec 6, 2005" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Hello Cruel World, docs and fonts, 1 Sept 2005" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "HCW, 4/18/06", 2006 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Hidden: A Gender by Kate Bornstein" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Hurricane of 38", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "I-Dark Roots, Inner Blonde backup, 11/15/00", 2000 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Julia Serano Either/Or", 2002 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Justin V [?] Bond, Dendrophile, for Kate" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "July 05 photos, Akoya, fireworks, bus, stamp", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Kate and Barbara holiday slides: Africa, Australia, Costa Rica" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Kate at NY Public Library, June 06", 2006 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Kate at Wells, 2/19/07, by Casey Morgan", 2007 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Kate B Lives Thru This, keynote presentation", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Kate B. Pre-show 30 mins.", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Kate B. Pre-show 44 mins, 30 mins - start 6, 40 mins - start 3", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Kate Bornstein 2007" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Kate Bornstein is a Queer and Pleasant Danger: script, stills, posters, and keynote file presentation" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Kate Bornstein pre show 2007, 13 tracks, 51 minutes" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Kate Bornstein tour information, 2002-2003, contains multimedia files and text files" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Kate show, Language of Paradox", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Kate's tats 2005, Delirious and Desire" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Kate's Weimar make-up and tattoo convention, May 2008" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "KB NODA [?] ketnote to print;" contains keynote presented at Duke University, n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "KB pre-show, 42 mins", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "KB pre-show, 48 mins", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "KB pre-show (short), 8 tracks, 30 mins", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "KB on TV: dyke TV, Canada Discovery, Real Sex", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "KB words and info, 6/8/02", 2002 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Language of Paradox", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Language of Paradox: an arts residency intensive with Kate Bornstein", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Language of Paradox: a resident workshop with Kate Bornstein", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Leondar - Wright - Collage, March 04", 2004 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "MISC pix: Christine J, Isabel's, NYC, photos to sort/file, blizzard by B, TTB art", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Mona Lisa Schulz, MD, medical institute, phone reading 26-4-07, Kate Bornstein", 2007 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Opposite of Sex… Is Neither 1", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Opposite of Sex… Is Neither 2", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Princess Art", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Private Dicks", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Pug Unleashed, keynote file", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Pub Unleashed, keynote file incl. all media", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Queer and Pleasant Bytes and carts, 3/22/04", 2004 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "SIP 6.5, Strangers in Paradox backup, all as of JAN 7, 2003" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "SIP Act II", ca.2003 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "SOHO notes, backup from V5X", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Scientology NY opening and Death Is An Orgasm" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Stacey White, WYEP FM, Pittsburgh", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Strangers, backup thru 01/13/03", 2003 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Strangers pix", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Strangers pre-prod 7/01", 2001 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Strangers in Paradox 3.5 reading, APR 6, 02", 2002 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Strangers in Paradox 4.3, how Katie hears this piece as of 5/8/02", 2002 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Strangers in Paradox 4.3, soundtrack for SF reading 5/29/02", 2002 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Strangers in Paradox 4.5, for 5/29/02 reading", 2002 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Strangers in Paradox pre-prod, July 1", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Tasteofdic 06", 2006 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "This American Life", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "This Is My Mind" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Time Out Youth Cruel Keynote", n.d. (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Transfabulous festival, June 2007, 'on men, women, and the rest of us'" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Transfabulous festival, June 2007, 'transitions voices'" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "TTBIL sound cues" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "Woman In Aman's Suit, George Jessup", 2006 (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "XMAS 2001 presents, attic of work done" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "XMAS 2001 presents, temp attic" (Box 19)
  - CD-R: "XMAS 2002 by BC" (Box 19)
  - DVD: "3 vids 4 KB show: Laurie Anderson, daddy movie, follow their eyes" (Box 19)
  - DVD: "12 and holding M and V" (Box 19)
  - DVD: "Eulogy for Allen, 2 Jan 2009" (Box 19)
  - DVD: "Fresh Meat 2006, the Fifth Anniversary Transgender and Queer Performance Festival, June 15-17" (Box 19)
  - DVD: "Hello Cruel artwork library", n.d. (Box 19)
  - DVD: "Hello Cruel book, Sunday, August 28th, 2005" (Box 19)
  - DVD: "Hidden: A Gender (Box 19)
  - DVD: "Hidden: A Gender, June 1-3, 2007, perfomred at United Universalist Church, Auburn, ME" (Box 19)
  - DVD: "JE directs, 1st draft", n.d. (Box 19)
  - DVD: "John Emigh Directs 40 years of Brown Uiversity Theatre", n.d. (Box 19)
  - DVD: "John Emigh production pix", n.d. (Box 19)
  - DVD: "KB at Evergreen [State University]", n.d. (Box 19)
  - DVD: "Kate Bornstein is a Queer and Pleasant Danger - Disc 1" (Box 19)
  - DVD: "Kate Bornstein is a Queer and Pleasant Danger - Disc 2" (Box 19)
  - DVD: "Kate Bornstein: A Gender Outlaw" (Box 19)
  - DVD: "Perfect Fake", n.d. (Box 19)
  - DVD: "Taking the Last Drag;" contains performance by Kate Bornstein, 2003 (Box 19)
  - DVD: "Transjourney" (Box 19)
  - DVD (YES): "Southeatern Regional Youth Conference keynote address by Kate Bornstein", 2006 (Box 19)
  - DVD: "Videos, Brown reunion and Niagra Falls, May 2009" (Box 19)
  - DVD: "What Kate is writing as of 11 AUG 05", 2005 (Box 19)
  - VHS: "A Pathway to Greater Happiness", n.d. (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Adele Anderson showreel" (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Christine Jorgenson", n.d. (Box 20)
  - VHS: "CNBC Real Personal 8-25-93", 1993 (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Discovery Channell interview and b-roll" (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Discovery Channell 'Sex Files' gender show" (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Docudrag Productions 'outlaw' Alisa Lebow 05-17-94, 1994 (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Gender Outlaw, 30 minute extremely rough cut" (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Growing Up and Coming Out; Ed Wood documentary; Phil Donahue with Kate" (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Hidden: A Gender", 1989 (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Hidden: A Gender", 2002 (Box 20)
  - VHS: "It's A Lezzie Life", 1995 (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Joan Rivers Show 'Sexually Confused', 1993 (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Kate Bornstein Documentary by Green Dragon Productions" (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Kate Bornstein - Interview with LGTV of Rhode Island" (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Kate Bornstein - Joan Rivers Show, n.d. (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Kate Bornstein 'Living Without Gender' at Beloit College", 1999 (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Kate Bornstein Vancouver", 2001 (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Kate Bornstein's Hidden: A Gender - Brown University", 1990 (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Kate in Trinidad, May", 1988 (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Lesbian Bed Death (Stacy Foiles)", n.d. (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Lesbian Impress Card: A 'commercial by Ingrid Wilhite and Sue Bahns" (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Lily Tomlin 'Pervis - Ernestine'", n.d. (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Magic Theater 1986 voiceover; Winston; Winston; Project X 1991 Sono's Last" (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Marilyn Kagen Show, 'He's Not the Man I Married'", n.d. (Box 20)
  - VHS: "The Opposite Sex Is Neither by Kate Bornstein at Josie's Caberet and Juice Joint in San Francisco", 1993 (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Private Dicks: Men Exposed: An HBO Documentary by Thom Powers ad Meema Spadola", 1999 (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Straight Up", n.d. (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Taking the Last Drag (Kate Bornstein): LGBT Community Center", 2003 (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Thank You Kate Bornstein (Mark Kenneth Woods)", 2000 (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Tom's Flesh" (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Two Brides and a Scalpel: Diary of a Lesbian Marriage;" contains signed VHS case (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Virtually Yours", n.d. (Box 20)
  - VHS: "Zen Pussy: A Meditation on Eleven Vulvas by Annie Sprinkle and Joseph Kramer" (Box 20)
- Restricted - CLOSED UNTIL JANUARY 1, 2039
  - Correspondence from Caitlin Sullivan, ca.1992 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Health file: correspondence and memos re: Bornstein's general physical health, 2006-2012 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Health file: "medical documents re: transition", 1985-1986 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Health file: mental health/therapy materials, 2010 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Health file: mental health/therapy materials, 2011 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Health file: mental health/therapy materials, 2013 (Box 20, Folder 6)